Will Jenkins (Murray Leinster) Papers
Will Jenkins (Murray Leinster) Papers
1915-1968
Jenkins, Will, 1896-1975.
35.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author of adventure, detective, Western, and science fiction short stories and novels, most of then written under the name Murray Leinster. Collection includes correspondence with authors, fans, literary agents, periodical editors, and publishers (1920-1967); and typescript and/or published articles, short stories, and books. Notable correspondents include Forrest J. Ackerman, Alonzo Dean Cole, Viola Irene Cooper, Roger Elwood, Harold Hersey, Frederik Pohl, Percy Waxman, and Mort Weisinger.
149081
Biographical History
William Fitzgerald Jenkins (1896-1975), better known to science fiction readers by his pseudonym Murray Leinster, was an American author of adventure, detective, Western, and science fiction short stories and novels. He is best known for his science fiction and alternate history work (he is credited with the invention of parallel universe stories); these won numerous awards and accolades, including the Liberty Award (1937), Hugo Award (1956), and a retro-Hugo (1996). The Sidewise Award for Alternate History, established in 1995, was named after his short story "Sidewise in Time."
Jenkins was born in Norfolk, Virginia on June 16, 1896 to George Briggs Jenkins and his wife Mary Louis Murray Jenkins. After attending public and private schools in Norfolk, Jenkins served during World War I with the Committee on Public Information and with the 98th Division of the United States Army and during World War II as an editor in the Office of War Information.
From 1915 to 1932 Jenkins wrote short stories for pulp and science fiction magazines under the pseudonym Murray Leinster. After 1930 he resumed the use of his own name for stories published in national magazines. Other pseudonyms include William Fitsgerald, Louisa Carter Lee, and Jean Farquar. He also wrote as Major Owen Hatteras, a "house name" often used by H. L. Mencken in their Smart Set magazine, for which Jenkins wrote fillers, epigrams, poems, etc.
Bibliographies of Jenkins' work are widely available online; see for example the listing for Murray Leinster on fantasticfiction.co.uk and the Murray Leinster page at www.sfsite.com.
Jenkins' works have been published in fifteen languages and Braille, and have appeared in numerous anthologies. He also wrote the screenplays for more than a dozen movies, including Owner of the Aztec and Murder Will Out.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Will Jenkins (Murray Leinster) Papers consists of correspondence, writings, ephemera and published material.
Correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, is with authors, fans, literary agents, periodical editors, and publishers. The letters relate particularly to Jenkins' activities as a writer, although letters from Bruce Crawford (1932-1933) are concerned with his views on Communism and on Presidents Hoover and Roosevelt. Notable correspondents include Forrest J Ackerman, Alonzo Deen Cole, Viola Irene Cooper, Bruce Crawford, Roger Elwood, Harold Hersey, Frederik Pohl, Percy Waxman, and Mort Weisinger.
Writings consists of the manuscripts for articles, books and short stories by Jenkins. Many were published under the Murray Leinster name, and a few under other pseudonyms. Where correspondence is present concerning a particular item, it is filed with the item and the folder labeled accordingly. Information on published versions is indicated when known. In a few cases all that is present is the published version. A partial bibliography, prepared in the 1960s and therefore incomplete, may be found at the beginning of this section and unidentified material at the end.
Manuscripts of others contains of approximately 25 manuscripts by other authors. Notable names include Robert Block, Ray Bradbury, Daphne Du Maurier and Anthony Wilson.
Ephemera contains programs from various events.
Published material consists of scattered issues of a number of science fiction magazines and fanzines. Of particular interest to researchers may be the complete index to Ace Books by Roger Alan Cox (Oct 1964), an index to science fiction magazines (1962), and an index to the first 31 issues of Science Fiction Review. Titles include Fanscient, First Fandom, Galactic Outpost, Mana, Scientification, Titania and more. There are also two items from the Publications of the Institute of Twenty-First Century Studies.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by name or title.
Related Material
has the papers of several science fiction authors and publishers as well as collections of science fiction fanzines and ephemera. Please refer to for a complete listing. In addition, our Rare Books holdings contain a considerable number of cataloged items relating to science fiction; please search for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Popular culture; Science fiction; Ackerman, Forrest J.; Bloch, Robert, 1917-1994.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-2012.; Cole, Alonzo Dean.; Cooper, Viola Irene.; Du Maurier, Daphne, 1907-1989.; Elwood, Roger.; Hersey, Harold Brainerd, 1893-1956.; Jenkins, Will, 1896-1975.; Leinster, Murray, 1896-1975.; Pohl, Frederik.; Waxman, Percy.; Weisinger, Mort, 1915-1978.; Adventure stories, American.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Detective and mystery stories, American.; Novelists, American.; Popular literature -- United States.; Science fiction, American.; Short stories, American.; Western stories.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Fanzines.; Manuscripts for publication.; Radio scripts.; Television scripts.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William F. Jenkins, 1968, 1982, 1986, 1987.
Inventory
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Forrest J., 1931-1954 (Box 1)
  - Arkham House, 1948-1966 (Box 1)
  - Avon Publications, Inc., 1959-1968 (Box 1)
  - Bartholomew House, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Belmont Productions, Inc., 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Berkely Publishing Corp., 1959-1967 (Box 1)
  - Brewer, Warren & Putnam, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Bruce Publishing Co., 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Chaffin, Rafe C. (Dr.), 1951 (Box 1)
  - Cole, Alonzo Deen, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Colliers, 1944-1956 (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Viola Irene, 1931-1948; literary agent (Box 1)
  - Crawford, Bruce, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Crown Publishers, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Country Gentleman, 1937-1945 (Box 2)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1935-1939; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1940-1946; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., England, 1924-1937; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., England, 1938-1947 (Box 4)
  - Doubleday & Co., 1920-1967 (Box 4)
  - Elwood, Roger, 1964-1965; literary agent (Box 4)
  - Fan mail
    - Leinster Players, 1926; radio (Box 4)
    - On Writing, 1932; radio series (Box 4)
    - Prologue to the Moon, 1953; radio program (Box 4)
  - Fantasy Press, Inc., 1951-1955 (Box 4)
  - Fantasy Publishing Co., 1948-1951 (Box 4)
  - Fantasy & Science Fiction, 1955-1965 (Box 4)
  - Farrar, Strauss and Cudahy, Inc., 1949-1959 (Box 4)
  - Fawcett Publications, 1924-1961 (Box 4)
  - Frederick Fell, Inc., 1949-1955 (Box 4)
  - Foley and Gordon, Inc., 1951 (Box 4)
  - Gnome Press, 1954-1964 (Box 4)
  - Goldfrank, James P., 1970-1976 (Box 4)
  - Hardy, Robert Thomas, 1921-1926; author's agent; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Hardy, Robert Thomas, 1927-1931; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Hardy, Robert Thomas, 1932-1938; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Hersey, Harold, 1919-1952 (Box 6)
  - International Press Bureau, 1936-1946 (Box 6)
  - Janifer, Laurence M., 1965; literary agent (Box 6)
  - Klein, Abe, 1950-1962; literary agent (Box 6)
  - Liberty, 1935-1955 (Box 6)
  - Life Story magazine, 1942-1945 (Box 6)
  - Littauer and Wilkinson, 1958-1967; literary agent (Box 6)
  - Love Story magazine, 1921-1924 (Box 7)
  - Macfadden-Bartell Corp., 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Macmillan Co., 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Matson, Harold, 1945-1961; literary agent (Box 7)
  - Meredith, Scott, 1949-1966; literary agent (Box 7)
  - Mondadori Publishing Co., 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Morris, Frank, 1937-1941 (Box 7)
  - National Broadcasting Co. (NBC), 1946-1952 (Box 7)
  - New American Library, 1959-1961 (Box 7)
  - W. W. Norton Co., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Plagiarism, 1933-1943 (Box 7)
  - Pocket Books, 1952-1964 (Box 7)
  - Pohl, Frederick, 1948-1965 (Box 7)
  - Pyramid Books, 1960-1967 (Box 7)
  - Random House, 1950-1964 (Box 7)
  - Paul R. Reynolds, Inc., 1950-1965 (Box 7)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1922-1961 (Box 7)
  - Science fiction fan clubs, 1936-1961 (Box 7)
  - Shasta Publishers, 1947-1959 (Box 8)
  - Standard Magazines, Inc., 1934-1964 (Box 8)
  - Screenplays, 1920-1938 (Box 8)
  - Schwartz, Julius, 1933-1936; literary agent (Box 8)
  - Science World, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Terrell, Rogers, 1948-1963; literary agent (Box 8)
  - To-day's Woman, 1945-1963 (Box 8)
  - Toronto Star Weekly, 1945-1956 (Box 8)
  - Veterans' Hospital Radio and Television Guide, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Association of Teachers of English, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Authors' Yearbook, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Waxman, Percy, 1933-1934 (Box 8)
  - Weisinger, Mort, 1934-1937 (Box 8)
  - Western, 1948-1953 (Box 8)
  - Wilck, Laura D., 1920-1924 (Box 8)
  - Writers Magazine, 1919-1954 (Box 8)
  - Ziff-Davis Publishing Co., 1959-1965 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1964 (Box 8)
- Writings
  - Bibliography of science fiction stories, Fanscient, vol. 3 no. 1, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Absence makes, Liberty Magazine, 1945 (Box 9)
  - Achilles' moustache, a story of the Cafe LaFarge, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 9)
  - According to the sailing directory, The Danger Trail, 1927 (Box 9)
  - The accursed hill (Box 9)
  - Adam's Eve, True Confessions, 1924 (Box 9)
  - Adapter, Astounding Stories, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Adobe walls, 1958; includes correspondence (Box 9)
  - After two cigarettes, Adventure, 1934 (Box 9)
  - Afterpiece, Argosy, 1940 (Box 9)
  - The agent: help or hindrance?, Editor, 1921; article (Box 9)
  - Airways obstructors, ltd., Wings, 1932; writing as William Murray (Box 9)
  - The Albemarle, Complete Stories, 1919 (Box 9)
  - Alice, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 9)
  - The aliens, Astounding, August 1959; television script; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - The amateur alchemist, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1954 (Box 9)
  - American inventory, television script (Box 9)
  - The ambulance made two trips, Astounding Stories, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Ample water, Sunset, 1924-1925; also syndicated (1925) (Box 10)
  - An insult to the family, Saturday Evening Post, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Android, Reknown Publications, 1957 (Box 10)
  - The anti-climax, Smart Set, 1916 (Box 10)
  - Apron strings [alternate title: Son-in-law], Today's Woman, 1944 (Box 10)
  - Apuru, Adventure Magazine, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Argument, True Experience, 1924[?] (Box 10)
  - As it turns out, Telling Tales, 1922 (Box 10)
  - The asphalt jungle, Movie Magazine (Box 10)
  - The ass, Pleiades Club Year Book, 1918-1919 (Box 10)
  - Assignment on Pasik, Thrilling Wonder Stories, February 1949 (Box 10)
  - Assisted by the Cucaracha Kid, Story Book and Chicago Ledger, 1922 (Box 10)
  - Atmosphere, Argosy, 1917 (Box 10)
  - Attention Saint Patrick, Astounding, January 1960. (Box 10)
  - Aztec gold [alternate title: Plenty of adventure], Fighting Romances, 1925 (Box 10)
  - Background count [alternate title: Deadly dust], Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Bad luck (Box 10)
  - Bad man (Box 10)
  - The bad nigger mood, Scribner's, 1936; includes galley proof (Box 10)
  - A bad one for an enemy, American Magazine, 1947 (Box 10)
  - The bad Samaritan [alternate title: Conscience], Collier's, 1936 (Box 10)
  - Baldy rides a hunch, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1921 (Box 10)
  - Balkan strategy, Elks Magazine [alternate title: Artist], 1943 (Box 10)
  - The barrier, Super Science Fiction, 1952 (Box 11)
  - The battle of the bunkhouse, Popular Pub. (Box 11)
  - Be young again, Fantasy Science Fiction, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Beast (Box 11)
  - Beats Big Shot's one finger, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1932 (Box 11)
  - Beautiful drip [alternate title: Letter from Chris], Today's Woman, 1945 (Box 11)
  - The beautiful thing, The Smart Set, 1919; one-act play; includes correspondence (Box 11)
  - Beautiful widow [alternate title: Captain Morgan], Collier's, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Because of her face, Saucy Stories, 1917 (Box 11)
  - The beleaguered Christmas, Love Story Magazine, 1921[?] (Box 11)
  - The bell boy (Box 11)
  - Benevolence of Suzanne, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 11)
  - The bell of Virgil, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 11)
  - The betrothal of Juana [alternate title: Portrait of a young lady of rank], Woman's Home Companion (Box 11)
  - Between moves, Collier's, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Beyond the sphinx's cave, Astounding Stories, 1933 (Box 11)
  - Beyond Tunnibuli, incomplete (Box 11)
  - Big Dan comes back, Top Notch (Box 11)
  - The big idea, Holland's Magazine, Grand Magazine, 1926; 1927 (Box 11)
  - The big lift, Movie Magazine (Box 11)
  - The big mob, International Detective Stories, 1933 (Box 11)
  - The big steal, Movie Magazine (Box 11)
  - Biography, Country Gentleman, 1941 (Box 11)
  - The black hand, Movie Magazine (Box 11)
  - The black rattlesnake [alternate title: slippers for Lily Red Fawn], Adventure, 1939 (Box 12)
  - The black rose, Movie Magazine (Box 12)
  - Black sheep, Adventure magazine, 1927; also published as book (Julian Messner, 1936) (Box 12)
  - The black stone of Aghart, Short Stories, 1930 (Box 12)
  - The blue lagoon, Movie Magazine (Box 12)
  - Board fence, Argosy, 1937 (Box 12)
  - Body and soul, Movie Magazine (Box 12)
  - Bolton the Great, This Week, 1942[?] (Box 12)
  - Book dust, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 12)
  - Boots, Adventure, 1929 (Box 12)
  - Borneo devils, Amazing, 1933 (Box 12)
  - The boss of the Flying Y, Top Notch (Box 12)
  - The bought wife, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 12)
  - The boy, Argosy, 1935 (Box 12)
  - A boy is not a man, Radio TV Mirror, 1956 (Box 12)
  - The boy with green hair, Movie Magazine (Box 12)
  - The boys in the bunkhouse, Triple X Western, 1927 (Box 12)
  - Brady makes a pinch, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1931 (Box 13)
  - Brains, Mystery Magazine, 1929 (Box 13)
  - The brief case, Cosmopolitan, 1940 (Box 13)
  - The broadcasts from nowhere, Galaxy (Box 13)
  - Broken arrow, Movie Magazine (Box 13)
  - Broken engagement [alternate title: Romance], Collier's, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Brotherly love (Box 13)
  - Buck comes home, Short Stories, 1939 (Box 13)
  - Bucket full of midnight, People's, 1923 (Box 13)
  - Bull's-eye, People’s, 1922 (Box 13)
  - Burglar's luck, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 13)
  - Burl, Argosy, 1919; novelette (Box 13)
  - Business is pleasure, Argosy, 1922 (Box 13)
  - A cabin in the wilderness, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1918 (Box 13)
  - Cafe LaFarge, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 13)
  - Captain China, Movie Magazine (Box 13)
  - Captain Horatio Hornblower, Movie Magazine (Box 13)
  - Captain Morgan was a gentleman, Short Stories, 1945 (Box 13)
  - Captains all, Collier's, 1940 (Box 13)
  - Caravan [alternate title: The kid], Collier's, 1935 (Box 13)
  - Career, Liberty, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Carefulness, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 13)
  - Cargo to Cape Town, Movie Magazine (Box 13)
  - Carrier based, Elks Magazine, 1943 (Box 14)
  - The case of the Dona Clotilde, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 14)
  - Casey, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 14)
  - Castaway [alternate title: Contempt], Argosy, 1946 (Box 14)
  - Castaway, Amazing Stories, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Castaway, 1946-1947; radio script for NBC; includes correspondence (Box 14)
  - The castaways, Smart Set, 1915 (Box 14)
  - The cat with the broken nose, Sir (Box 14)
  - Challenge to Lassie, Movie Magazine (Box 14)
  - Charley's partner, Short Stories, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Chasing trouble [alternate title: Tanana trail], Collier's, 1936 (Box 14)
  - Checkpoint lambda, Berkeley Publications, circa 1965; book, incomplete; original with corrections, carbons copy; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - A Christmas in Virginia, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 14)
  - A Christmas story, Southern Magazine, 1949 (Box 14)
  - Circus people, This Week, 1935 (Box 14)
  - City gangster raid, Triple X Western (Box 14)
  - City of the blind, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1929; no. 2 of the "Darkness" series (Box 14)
  - City on the moon [alternate title: Space ferry], Ace Books, 1953; 1960; Bouregy, in German; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - The clay pigeon (Box 15)
  - The cocoanut octopod, Dream World, 1924 (Box 15)
  - The coming of the angel, Snappy Stories, 1920; includes correspondence (Box 15)
  - Command decision, Movie Magazine (Box 15)
  - Coney Island murders, Black Bat, 1933; includes correspondence (Box 15)
  - Connie Lancefield's secret, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 15)
  - Constant lover [alternate title: By an unknown lover], Woman's Home Companion, 1949 (Box 15)
  - Cops think crooks are fools, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1933 (Box 15)
  - The Corianis disaster (Box 15)
  - Coroner's flats, Movie Magazine (Box 15)
  - A couple of nice kids (Box 15)
  - The Cow Creek murder, Mystery Stories, 1928 (Box 16)
  - The coward, Detective Story Magazine, 1922; includes correspondence (Box 16)
  - Crazy, Standard Magazine (Box 16)
  - Crazy marriage, Collier's (Box 16)
  - Creature of the abyss, Berkley Publications, 1961; includes correspondence (Box 16)
  - Crime on Tristan, Argosy, 1936 (Box 16)
  - Critical difference, Astounding Stories, 1954; also appeared in Colonial Survey Stories (Gnome Press) and Planet Explorer (Avon, 1957) (Box 16)
  - The crooked way, Movie Magazine (Box 16)
  - Cupid, M.D., Love Stories, 1921 (Box 16)
  - D. Slocum, gall, wormwood and general detecting, Argosy, 1922 (Box 16)
  - Dallas, Fawcett Gold Medal, 1950; novel; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Dames, Short Stories, 1939 (Box 17)
  - Dark continent, Cosmopolitan (Box 17)
  - Dark universe, Startling Stories, 1949; also appeared in Galaxy Science Fiction Novels (1954) (Box 17)
  - Darkness on Fifth Avenue, Argosy, 1929; Adventure Novels, 2/37 (Box 17)
  - The day of the deepies, 1947; 1949; includes correspondence (Box 17)
  - De profundis, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1945; also published in Sidewise in Time (Avon, 1952) (Box 17)
  - Dead city, Thrilling Wonder Stories, also published in Sidewise in Time (Avon, 1952) (Box 17)
  - A dead man started it, Triple X Western, 1932 (Box 17)
  - Dead man’s isle, All Star Detective Stories (Box 17)
  - Dead on arrival, Movie Magazine (Box 17)
  - Dear Charles, Standard Magazine, 1952; also published in Sidewise in Time (Avon, 1952) (Box 17)
  - The death bird sings, Ace High, 1921 (Box 17)
  - Death which is mah profits, incomplete (Box 17)
  - Deep sea trail, Adventure, 1929; see also The lonely sea (Box 17)
  - Deep sea trail, 1959; novel (Box 17)
  - Deputy, Standard Magazine, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Desert lover, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 18)
  - Design for heaven, Toronto Star, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Destiny is respectable, Argosy, 1932 (Box 18)
  - The devil of East Lupton, Vermont, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Devil-devil stone, Adventure, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Did you ever think, The Editor, article (Box 18)
  - Dimension X, NBC, 1950; scripts for two episodes of the radio program, "The Lost Race" (ep. 7, 20 May 1950) and "A Logic Named Joe" (ep. 13, 1 Jul 1950) (Box 18)
  - The dimpled knees of Nanette, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 18)
  - Diocesan report, Argosy, 1946 (Box 18)
  - The disciplinary circuit, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1945-1946; also published in The Last Spaceship, Fell, 1949; includes correspondence (Box 18)
  - Doctor (Box 18)
  - Doctor to the stars book 1, "Grand Father's War," Pyramid Publications, 1961; as published in Astounding, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Doctor to the stars book 2, "Med Ship Man," Pyramid Publications, 1961; also published in Galaxy, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Doctor to the stars book 3, "Tallien Three," Pyramid Publications, 1963; also published in Astounding, 1963 as "Hate disease" (Box 19)
  - Doesn't it make you mad, Saucy Stories, 1919; poem (Box 19)
  - Dog story, McLean's, 1943 (Box 19)
  - Doomsday deferred [alternate title: Soldados], Saturday Evening Post, 1949; 1966; includes correspondence (Box 19)
  - The double house, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 19)
  - Double murder (Box 19)
  - Down to the sea in ships, Movie Magazine (Box 19)
  - The dream [alternate title: The verdict], 1944 (Box 19)
  - The dream of Sungi Gut, Adventure, 1934 (Box 19)
  - Dreams and Life,Smart Set, 1916; two poems, written under the pseudonym Jean Farquar (Box 19)
  - The Duc de Luneville, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 19)
  - Dude ranch murder [alternate title: Trouble on the dude ranch], Black Bat, 1933; includes correspondence (Box 19)
  - Duplicators [alternate title: Revolt of the Uffts], Ace Books, 1963; also published in Worlds of Tomorrow Magazine (1963); 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Dusk to daylight [alternate title: Dusk to dawn], Collier's, 1940 (Box 20)
  - Dust and nuggets and furs, Ace High, 1922 (Box 20)
  - East of Java, Movie Magazine (Box 20)
  - Editorials, Standard Magazine, 1952; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Eduardo's parrot, Young's, 1921 (Box 20)
  - Ellen, Young's, 1922 (Box 20)
  - The emerald Buddha, Short Stories, 1929 (Box 20)
  - Emergency for Doctor Hamlin [alternate title: Interne], Saturday Evening Post, 1941; 1950; includes correspondence (Box 20)
  - The end, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1946; also published in Twists in Time (Avon, 1946) (Box 20)
  - The end of the trail, Ace High, 1922 (Box 20)
  - The ending of El Jefe, Black Mask, 1927 (Box 20)
  - Ending with honor [alternate title: Ending], Collier's, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Enemy of the state [alternate title: Party member], Collier's, 1937 (Box 20)
  - The envelope, Telling Tales, 1922 (Box 20)
  - Epigrams, Snappy Stories, 1915 (Box 20)
  - Epigrams, Smart Set, 1916 (Box 20)
  - Epigrams, Smart Set, 1917 (Box 20)
  - Epigrams, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 20)
  - Epigrams, Smart Set, 1921 (Box 20)
  - The eternal now, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1944; 1964; includes correspondence (Box 20)
  - Ethical equations, Astounding Stories, 1945 (Box 20)
  - Eusebius the Cenobite, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 20)
  - Everything's right, Detective Fiction Weekly (Box 20)
  - Eviadne's undies, Ace, 1923 (Box 20)
  - Evidence, Argosy, 1918 (Box 20)
  - Evidence, Black Mask, 1922 (Box 20)
  - The evil god, Ace High, 1921 (Box 20)
  - Ex-con, Top Notch (Box 20)
  - Exile, Country Gentleman, 1940 (Box 20)
  - Exploration team, Astounding Stories, 1955; also published in Colonial Survey Stories (Gnome Press) and Planet Explorer (Avon, 1957) (Box 20)
  - The extra intelligence, Argosy, 1935 (Box 21)
  - The eye of black A’wang, Short Stories, 1929 (Box 21)
  - Eyes of the eagle, Flynn's Detective Fiction Weekly, 1924 (Box 21)
  - Fame and Mr. Meekan, Top Notch, 1925 (Box 21)
  - Fate, Young's, 1921 (Box 21)
  - Fate doesn't care [alternate title: Handcuffs], Collier's, 1941; includes correspondence (Box 21)
  - Fate doesn't care, NBC, 1947; radio script, mimeographed copy (Box 21)
  - Father hates the sheriff, Nugget, 1953 (Box 21)
  - Father-in-law (Box 21)
  - Favor to a lady [alternate title: Favor to a wench], Collier's, 1936 (Box 21)
  - The fear planet [alternate title: Thing from the sky], Super Science, 1950; also published in The Aliens (Berkley Press, 1960) (Box 21)
  - Fever, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 21)
  - The fifth dimension catapult, Astounding Stories, 1930-1931; includes correspondence (Box 21)
  - The fifth dimension tube, Astounding Stories, 1933; includes correspondence (Box 21)